const e="We could not find what you asked for, but got you this",a="commerce",t=200,o=120,i=[{id:101,question:"question",option:{a:"optiona",b:"optionb",c:"optionc",d:"optiond"},section:"",image:"image",answer:"answer",solution:"solution",examtype:"utme",examyear:"examye"},{id:788,question:"One of the obstacles  to achieving the objectives of ECOWAS is",option:{a:"lack of a common currency",b:"colonial linkages",c:"sovereignty of states",d:"language differences."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:411,question:"A person who undertakes a life insurance is said to be an ",option:{a:"Insurer ",b:"assurer ",c:"assured ",d:"insured "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:176,question:"A distinctive advantage of GSM is its ",option:{a:"mobility",b:" cost   ",c:"stability   ",d:"coverage."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:709,question:"Ocean liners are subdivided into",option:{a:"passenger liners and cargo liners",b:"coastal liners and cargo liners",c:"cargo liners and tramp liners",d:"passenger liners and tramp liners."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000"},{id:766,question:"The major difference between insurance and assurance is that while insurance",option:{a:"takes care of uncertainty, assurance takes care of risks",b:"takes care of risks, assurance takes care  uncertainty",c:"hinges on probabilities, assurance is based on possibilities",d:"is about indemnity assurance is about life in the future."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:815,question:"A bill of exchange already accepted can be discounted by the holder in",option:{a:"the central bank",b:"at least two banks",c:"his bank",d:"any bank."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:412,question:"Tourism serves the purpose of ",option:{a:"cross-cultural understanding and peaceful interaction ",b:"opening avenues for leaving the country",c:"economic development and naturalization ",d:"exploiting the country’s natural endowment"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:416,question:"In case of liquidation of a public limited liability company, those that are first paid are ",option:{a:"ordinary shareholders ",b:"preference shareholders ",c:"cumulative preference shareholders ",d:"debenture holders"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:758,question:"The major procedures in the purchase and sale of goods are enquiry",option:{a:"quotation, order and invoice",b:"placement, order and invoice",c:"bargain, order and invoice",d:"order, sale and invoice."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:745,question:"Which of the following services does a lawyer render?",option:{a:"industrial services",b:"indirect services",c:"direct services",d:"commercial services."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:635,question:"The Organization of Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC) is an example of a",option:{a:"cartel",b:"trust",c:"holding company",d:"consortium"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1990"},{id:743,question:"A distinguishing characteristic of labour is that it is",option:{a:"constant",b:"expensive",c:"mobile",d:"cheap"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:295,question:"The wealth of a nation depend on the volume of its",option:{a:"bilateral trade activities",b:"commercial activities",c:"multilateral trade activities",d:"stock market"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:706,question:"The current trends in retailing competition in Nigeria are",option:{a:"advertising and sales promotion strategies",b:"branding, enterprising and differentiation of goods and services",c:"self-service, after-sales services and branding strategies",d:"after-sales services and sales promotion strategies."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000"},{id:354,question:"Balance of payment problems arise if a country’s ",option:{a:"exports is more than imports",b:"imports is more than exports",c:"currently is devaluated",d:"Invisible exports is more than visible exports "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:817,question:"Given:  I.Retail; II.Export; III.Transport; IV.Import; V.Insurance; VI.Banking and finance; VII. Wholesale; VIII. Communication. Which of the above are aids to trade?",option:{a:"I, II,  III and VIII",b:"III, V, VI and VIII",c:"I, II, III and VI",d:"II, V, VI and VII"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:858,question:"The process of dividing tasks into jobs and departments and of delegating authority is known as",option:{a:"staffing",b:"leading",c:"directing",d:"organizing"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:813,question:"The Stock Exchange is a market where",option:{a:"long-term securities are sold",b:"all types of securities are sold",c:"short-term securities are sold",d:"medium-term securities are sold."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:419,question:"The portion of the authorized share capital given out to the public for subscription is ",option:{a:"called-up capital ",b:"issued capital ",c:"paid up capital ",d:"reserved capital "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:347,question:"Services rendered to the public is provided by ",option:{a:"Government ",b:"civil servants ",c:"professionals ",d:"domestic servants "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:793,question:"Which of the following best describes the scope of commerce?",option:{a:"All forms of commercial exchanges and the manufacturing industry",b:"Buying and selling and the construction industry",c:"All occupational exchanges relating to industries and commercial activities",d:"Buying and selling as well as the extraction of natural resources."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:178,question:"The major determinant of fire insurance premium is the ",option:{a:"type and structure of the property to be insured ",b:"usefulness of the property to the owner",c:"owner of the property to be insured",d:"extent of fire damage anticipated."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:587,question:"Which of the following towns was NOT an initial commercial centre in Nigeria?",option:{a:"Kano",b:"Lagos",c:"Maiduguri",d:"Yola"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:11,question:"The members of the Niger Basin Commission  include  ",option:{a:"Guinea, Ghana and Niger Republic",b:"Burkina Faso, Guinea and Nigeria ",c:"The Gambia, Benin Republic and Chad Republic",d:" Nigeria, The Gambia and Cameroon"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:413,question:"The type of letters that are delivered through the normal mail or by airmail express service is referred to as ",option:{a:"Inland letters ",b:"registered letters",c:"airmail letters",d:"express letters"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:693,question:"One of the major reasons for merger is to",option:{a:"reduce the number of unskilled manpower",b:"increase the number of skilled manpower.",c:"prevent liquidation.",d:"liberalize the market."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:585,question:"The first step for a businessman who wishes to engage in international trade is to",option:{a:"ask the exporter to move the goods to the shipping company for delivery",b:"engage the services of clearing agent to clear the goods on his behalf",c:"establish contact with the foreign trading partner",d:"fill an application for import form with a bank"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:671,question:"When expenses on trading are deducted, the result is the",option:{a:"rate of turn over",b:"net profit",c:"gross profit",d:"cost of goods sold."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:214,question:"A trader who gives credit stands to enjoy ",option:{a:"higher profit ",b:"cash discount ",c:"increased sales ",d:"trade discount"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:163,question:"A major advantage of a cooperative society is that it ",option:{a:"gives members the opportunity to unite",b:"draws members closer to government",c:"promotes awareness among members",d:"encourages thrift among members."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:285,question:"The efficiency of an organization is enhanced by ",option:{a:"government assistance ",b:"the host community ",c:"customer support ",d:"skilled manpower "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:141,question:"The major types of warehouses are ",option:{a:"manufacturer, bonded, departmental and private  ",b:"bonded, public, cold room and private",c:"manufacturer, bonded, public and departmental",d:"wholesaler, manufacturer, public and bonded."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:666,question:"A document that serves as an instrument for preferential tariff is referred to as",option:{a:"an indent",b:"a certificate of origin",c:"a consular invoice",d:"an advice note."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:237,question:"The coordinating section of the central processing unit that manages the flow of data is the ",option:{a:"arithmetic logic unit",b:"control unit",c:"magnetic unit",d:"register"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:156,question:"Which of the following best describes inputs for any production activity?   ",option:{a:"Natural resources.",b:" Business resources.",c:"Human resources.",d:"Material resources."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:62,question:"The difference between personal selling and sales promotion is that while sales promotion includes free gifts and samples, personal selling involves",option:{a:"distributing instructional posters",b:"face-to-face communication with customers",c:"premium programming for customers",d:"publishing promotional booklets."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:881,question:"Banks are engaged in the business of buying and selling of",option:{a:"bills of exchange",b:"instruments of credit",c:"intangible products",d:"land"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:137,question:"The most important advantage of privatization is the enhancement of ",option:{a:"liquidity ",b:"accountability",c:"profitability  ",d:"efficiency."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:478,question:"A motor dealer who agreed to sell a car to Mr. X but sold and delivered it to Mr. Y on the delivery date agreed with Mr. X. He has discharged the contract by ",option:{a:"performance ",b:"frustration ",c:"an agreement ",d:"breach "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:75,question:"An acquired firm in a merger will always receive a",option:{a:" premium  ",b:" grant ",c:"share ",d:"discount"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:750,question:"Entrusting the management of a company to the courts to enable the settlement of the company’s obligations is an indication of",option:{a:"distress",b:"closure",c:"bankruptcy",d:"liquidation."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:589,question:"Bridging the gap between producers and consumers is the sole purpose of",option:{a:"distribution",b:"hawking",c:"retailing",d:"warehousing"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:315,question:"A businessman who undertakes the hull insurance policy is aiming at ",option:{a:"covering losses on damages to the cargo ",b:"protecting injured crew in the ship ",c:"averting payment of the freight ",d:"covering damages to the body of the ship "},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:561,question:"Which of these is NOT a source of capital to First Bank of Nigeria Plc?",option:{a:"Equipment leasing",b:"Lean from friends",c:"Profit plough back",d:"Sales of shares"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:219,question:"Balance of payments is made up of ",option:{a:"visible  and current  items ",b:"invisible and capital items ",c:"current and capital items",d:"visible and invisible items"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:228,question:"Personal selling is used for the purpose of ",option:{a:"establishing the company ",b:"providing information ",c:"creating product awareness",d:"launchers "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:170,question:"An economic activity which deals with natural resources is a form of  ",option:{a:"extraction",b:"refining   ",c:"construction ",d:"manufacturing."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:460,question:"The amount of authorized capital that shareholders have subscribed to is ",option:{a:"issued share capital ",b:"authorized share capital ",c:"owner’s equity ",d:"working capital "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:830,question:"Securities on which the buyers are not issued with certificates are called",option:{a:"authorized securities",b:"inscribed securities",c:"bearer securities",d:"registered securities."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:243,question:"A factor is a business environment which increases the rate of product obsolescence is ",option:{a:"technology ",b:"political",c:"legal ",d:"economic"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:504,question:"Which of the following is not a function of a retailer?",option:{a:"Supplying goods to final consumers",b:"Bulk breaking",c:"Giving information to the wholesaler",d:"Branding and packaging of goods"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2000"},{id:252,question:"The major components of modern retailing include ",option:{a:"branding, doorstep  selling and customer stimulation ",b:"branding, sales promotion and mail order ",c:"chain stores, customer stimulation and doorstep selling ",d:"branding, supermarkets and after-sales service"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:767,question:"A documentary bill will normally be accompanied by",option:{a:"sales invoice, bill of lading and insurance certificate",b:"clean bill, bill of lading and insurance certificate",c:"bill of lading, consular invoice and insurance certificate",d:"consular invoice, FOB certificate and bill of  lading."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:517,question:"A retirement insurance policy which enables the assured to receive income for a specific period is",option:{a:"annuity",b:"endowment",c:"whole life",d:"fidelity guarantee"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2000"},{id:428,question:"The promotion of team spirit in an organization is referred to as ",option:{a:"Unit of direction ",b:"spirit de corps ",c:"unity of purpose",d:"discipline "},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:658,question:"The type of wholesaler that combines selling, delivery and collection in one operation is",option:{a:"specialist   wholesaler",b:"rack jobber",c:"drop shipment",d:"truck. wholesaler"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:747,question:"One major advantage of a credit and thrift cooperative is that",option:{a:"it can approach government for a loan",b:"it encourages saving habits",c:"there are no legal restrictions",d:"each member has a vote during meetings."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:3,question:"The program that makes up the operating system in a computer is         ",option:{a:"micro program",b:"system flowchart",c:"system software",d:"syntax"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:708,question:"An invoice can be described as a",option:{a:"contractual agreement for the sale of goods",b:"document specifying quantity, description, prices and total value of purchases",c:"receipt containing necessary information about the goods",d:"letter specifying the contractual sales of goods between two parties."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000"},{id:361,question:"A cheque that has been drawn but not presented for payment can still be honoured ",option:{a:"within 6 months ",b:"after 9 months ",c:"within 9 months ",d:"after 6 months"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:596,question:"The ability of money to be divided into smaller units for easy exchange of goods and services explains",option:{a:"divisibility",b:"durability",c:"recognisability",d:"stability"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:637,question:"In insurance the term Uberrimaefidei stands for",option:{a:"utmost good faith",b:"subrogation",c:"insurable interest",d:"indemnity against loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1990"},{id:93,question:"The excess of the assets over the liabilities of a business is called ",option:{a:"working capital",b:"net worth ",c:"capital employed ",d:" initial capital"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:505,question:"A merchant who wishes to order goods from a foreign country sends",option:{a:"an invoice",b:"an indent",c:"an advice note",d:"a credit note"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2000"},{id:681,question:"An association that acts as a watchdog between  entrepreneurs and government to protect trade from any unfavourable laws is said",option:{a:"cartel",b:"syndicate",c:"Chamber of Commerce",d:"Nigeria Bar Association."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:414,question:"A business organization that exploits the capabilities of a member to remedy the weaknesses of another is a ",option:{a:"joint venture ",b:"partnership ",c:"nominal partnership ",d:"cooperative "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:696,question:"Production involves",option:{a:"making goods available where and when needed",b:"changing the form of goods, moving and making them available as needed",c:"the manufacturing of goods and provision of services",d:"the assembling of all necessary parts to produce a finished product."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000"},{id:529,question:"Which of the following is a method of sales promotion?",option:{a:"Radio giggles",b:"Poster display",c:"Trade fair",d:"Television broadcast"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2000"},{id:606,question:"The oldest and commonest form of business in Nigeria is",option:{a:"partnership",b:"the co-operative society",c:"sole proprietorship",d:"joint stock venture"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1990"},{id:207,question:"An example of a cartel is ",option:{a:"OPEC",b:"ECOWAS ",c:"AU ",d:"EU"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:514,question:"Which of the following is a means of payment through the post office?",option:{a:"Standing Order",b:"Promissory note",c:"Money order",d:"Telegraphic transfer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2000"},{id:664,question:"One of the duties of the employer to his employee is to",option:{a:"delegate his duties to other staff",b:"charge the employee on the use of equipment",c:"serve faithfully and honestly",d:"provide job security."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:284,question:"An organizational structure that is military in nature is the ",option:{a:"line structure ",b:"staff structure ",c:"line and staff structure ",d:"functional structure "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:661,question:"Avast is an example of",option:{a:"a web browser",b:"a search engine",c:"an antivirus",d:"a spread sheet"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:740,question:"The instrument establishing the Economic Community of West African States in 1975 is",option:{a:"a decree",b:"an act",c:"a treaty",d:"constitution"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000"},{id:262,question:"The central bank differs from commercial banks  because it ",option:{a:"renders service to customers",b:"carriers but foreign exchange transactions ",c:"issues currencies ",d:"discounts bills"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:773,question:"The main factors that determine the value stock on the Stock Exchange are dividend an",option:{a:"the psychology of the market",b:"capital gain",c:"capital appreciation",d:"warrant payment"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:147,question:"The role of a wholesaler in the channel of distribution is to    ",option:{a:"produce goods in large quantities and sell in small quantities ",b:"buy goods directly from the manufacturers",c:"buy good in large quantities and sell in small quantities",d:"sell goods directly to the consumers "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:742,question:"The pivot on which the wheel of commerce rotates is",option:{a:"tariff",b:"trade",c:"taxation",d:"price."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:200,question:`Given: I. shoe marker    II. Policeman     III. Fisherman    IV. Gardener    V. Broker .    The persons engaged in primary occupation are 
`,option:{a:"I, III and IV ",b:"III and IV",c:"III and V",d:"I , II and V"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:837,question:"Which of the following determines the quality of goods that a retailer sells",option:{a:"The mode of contract of sales",b:"The type of manufacturer",c:"The regulations regarding sales in the area",d:"The location of his shop."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:789,question:"One of the main objectives of establishing the Niger River Basin Commission was to",option:{a:"embark on a comprehensive survey of the available water resources",b:"carry out research for the development of fresh water fisheries",c:"develop infrastructure to facilitate economic activities",d:"promote trade among member-states to improve standards of living."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:393,question:"An example of an activity in the construction industry is ",option:{a:"blacksmithing  ",b:"bricklaying ",c:"car assembling ",d:"shoemaking "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:832,question:"The principal objectives of the Central Bank of Nigeria can be classified broadly into",option:{a:"bankers’ bank, lender of last resort and issuance of currency",b:"service, currency management and financial intermediation",c:"banking services, foreign exchange operations and open",d:"markets operations service, monetary policy and developmental functions."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:474,question:"The essential utility derived from the use of a product is known as ",option:{a:"augmented benefit",b:"branded benefit ",c:"core benefit ",d:"formal benefit"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:539,question:"Commercialization is good for the Nigerian economy because it",option:{a:"creates room for competition",b:"increases the cost of living",c:"leads to the reduction of workforce",d:"leads to uneven distribution of wealth"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:423,question:"The main objective of a trade association is to ",option:{a:"protect is members against litigation ",b:"boost the trade of its members ",c:"secure credit for its members ",d:"protect its members against victimization "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:540,question:"Obtaining feedback on the quality and performance of competing products of different manufacturers, explains the retailer’s function of",option:{a:"after sales service",b:"granting to credits to consumers",c:"market research",d:"stocking variety of goods"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:827,question:"Which of the following is a function of employers’ association?",option:{a:"Undertaking research on behalf of employees",b:"Promotion of thrift in workers",c:"Promotion of workers’ welfare",d:"Dissemination of information through sponsored journals."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:433,question:"Yahaya bought a piece of furniture on a credit sale agreement from Ahmed and resold it to Ali before all installments were made. The court upheld that Ahmed could not recover possession of the items from Ali. The reason for the judement was because ",option:{a:"ownership was transferred on completion of installment ",b:"ownership was transferred on delivery ",c:"Yahaya could not pass title to a third party ",d:"Ali was still indebted to Yahaya"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:247,question:"The central focus of commercial activities is ",option:{a:"pricing   ",b:"advertising ",c:"trading ",d:"marketing "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:372,question:"An example of a trade association is ",option:{a:"ALGON",b:"NLC",c:"NURTW",d:"NULGE"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:600,question:"Which of the following statements is not true?",option:{a:"Commercial services are the life blood of a country economic system",b:"There cannot occur commercial services until goods have been produced.",c:"Without commercial services most goods and services will not be produced",d:"There is no stage of production that does not employ commercial services."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1990"},{id:41,question:"Loan schemes by thrift societies are ",option:{a:"mortgage schemes   ",b:"conventional schemes   ",c:"mutual schemes     ",d:"unconventional schemes "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:216,question:"A source of capital that has both elements of debt and equity is a ",option:{a:"debenture ",b:"warrant ",c:"loan ",d:"share"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:187,question:"A share premium is an example of",option:{a:"issued capital ",b:"capital stock ",c:"equity capital",d:"capital reserve."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:647,question:"The cost which is incurred as a result of failure to load or unload a ship at the ports within a specified period is referred to as",option:{a:"demurrage charges",b:"premium charges",c:"trade charges",d:"excess charges"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:143,question:"A shop which consists of many stores trading under a single roof and which stocks varieties of gods with each unit having its own head is a ",option:{a:"multiple shop  ",b:"supermarket ",c:"superstore",d:"departmental store."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:629,question:"Charges paid by a ship for staying at a port beyond agreed sailing time is called",option:{a:"profit",b:"interest",c:"holding",d:"demurrage"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1990"},{id:712,question:"Mr. Olatunde took up a fire insurance on a property valued at N 1000 and the amount insured is  N800. The property caught fire causing a loss of  N400. If the insurance was taken with the 	clause ‘with average’, what is the amount to be paid by the insurance company?",option:{a:"N320",b:"N420",c:"N460",d:"N560."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000"},{id:608,question:"Which of the following is not a factor of production?",option:{a:"Capital",b:"land",c:"Labour",d:"Staffing"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1990"},{id:472,question:"Management of a business involves he development of ideas for the ",option:{a:"distribution of goods and services that human wants",b:"transportation of goods and services that goods and services that human wants ",c:"transfer of little of ownership of goods and services to individuals.",d:"production of goods and services that satisfy human needs."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:368,question:"The business organization that can effectively combine management with control is ",option:{a:"private limited liability company ",b:"sole proprietorship ",c:"public limited liability company ",d:"co-operative society "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:273,question:"Partnerships are most effective where ",option:{a:"the partners are family friends ",b:"professionals are involved",c:"members can easily raise enough capital ",d:"government regulations are favourable "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:434,question:"The body which ensures that consumers are protected against harmful product in Nigeria is ",option:{a:"NAFDAC ",b:"NDLEA",c:"SON",d:"CPC"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:169,question:"A major criticism of a cooperative society is",option:{a:"limited capital ",b:"granting excessive loans to members   ",c:"selling goods on credit to non- members    ",d:"management incompetence."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:185,question:"The abbreviation C & F indicates that the",option:{a:"production cost excludes the cost of carriage",b:"selling price includes the cost of carriage",c:"cost of production includes delivery charges",d:"cost price includes the cost of carriage."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:78,question:"An engineer in government employ is to be rendering   ",option:{a:"primary service   ",b:"tertiary service ",c:"indirect service   ",d:"direct service. "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:538,question:"In which of the following classes of occupation would you place a doctor?",option:{a:"Extractive",b:"Commercial",c:"Direct services",d:"Indirect services"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2000"},{id:819,question:"A wholesaler who possesses the tittle to the goods he sells is known as",option:{a:"a merchant wholesaler",b:"a multiple wholesaler",c:"a general wholesaler",d:"an agent wholesaler."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:670,question:"In the transportation industry, dead freight is used to describe the",option:{a:"cost paid for an empty space left in the ship",b:"charge for each day a performance was delayed",c:"persons that hire a ship for a specific purpose.",d:"cost of shipping a particular cargo for a specific voyage"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:166,question:"A document which advertises the shares of a company is known as a  ",option:{a:"memorandum of satisfaction   ",b:"dividend warrant     ",c:"deed",d:"prospectus."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:847,question:"How much was the trade discount?",option:{a:"N42,500",b:"N27,500",c:"N22,500",d:"N20,000"},section:"Ojo purchased the following items from Sani at the specified prices on credit: 200 cartons of milk at N1,000 per carton; 150 bags of sugar at N500 per bag; 50 bags of rice at  N3 000 per bag. Sani allowed 10% trade discount and 5% cash discount, if payment is made within the agreed period. Ojo paid within the agreed period.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:432,question:"A person who in consideration for an extra commission, takes responsibility for goods sold on credit and in case of default is a ",option:{a:"commission agent",b:"del credere agent ",c:"broker ",d:"factor "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:695,question:"The major factors that facilitate merchandising are",option:{a:"communication, advertising and banking",b:"trading, warehousing and production",c:"management, insurance and advertising",d:"banking, insurance and transportation."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000"},{id:798,question:"A core investor in the current phase of privatization in Nigeria is one who",option:{a:"can afford to buy most the shares of the enterprises",b:"will be at the core of the enterprises",c:"can mobilize foreign currency equivalent to the value of the enterprises",d:"has the technical know-how of the enterprises"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:17,question:"Poor sewage disposal, oil spill and indiscriminate refuse dumping all ",option:{a:"lead to  land pollution",b:"water pollution   ",c:"land and water pollution",d:"air and water pollution"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:110,question:"An aspect of marketing that stimulates buying by providing free gifts is ",option:{a:" advertising  ",b:" personal selling ",c:"publicity ",d:" sales promotion,"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:272,question:"In a public limited liability company, planning is carried out by ",option:{a:"the chairman of the board ",b:"the board of directors ",c:"shareholders",d:"employees"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"}],n={message:e,subject:a,status:200,total:120,data:i};export{i as data,n as default,e as message,t as status,a as subject,o as total};
